Finding Aid for the Civil War Collection, 1840-1929 (bulk 1861-1865)
Buffalo History Museum. Research Library
- Records of War Dead, 1861-1875, X.
  - Affidavits [for pension requests, etc.], 1865-1875 (Box-folder 5.2)
    Collection of C. E. Young Papers
  - Lists of war dead from Orleans County (Box-folder 5.3)
    Civil War Journals, 1861-1866
- Muster and Descriptive Rolls for Erie County, 1861-1865, XI.
  - 3-year enlistments and soldiers' oaths, 1861-1862 (Box-folder 5.4)
    Letter to General Barry regarding artillery from Governor Folder #4 Washburn (Maine), November 23, 1861
    Letter to Captain Caldwell (5th N. Hampshire Volunteers) regarding need for equipment by various officers, October 25, 1862
  - Muster and descriptive roll, Erie County, 1865 (Box-folder 5.5)
    Names of Soldiers Who Died from Orleans County (Civil War) [Gift of E. T. Coann. Albion, New York]
    Proofs of Deaths of Civil War Pensioners: Michael Schweickhart (April 1865); Thomas Fleming (August, 1866); Sarah Hebard (July 1867); Levi Bishop (August 1869); George Kaph (March 1870) John Gleason (December, 1871) mud Marias Von Holsh (May 1875)
    Roll of Honor (Deaths; 1897-1898)
  - Muster and descriptive roll, Erie County, 1864-1865 (Box-folder 5.6)
    Ordinance (Facsimile): Secession of Mississippi, January 9, 1861
    List of Confederate Infantry Officers at Gloucester Pt., Virginia, July 9, 1861 [Enclosure] [Donated to B.H.S. by Jabich Harris (?) February 24, 1890]
    Muster Roll of Company C, l3th Regiment of North Carolina Troops, June 30, 1862
    Muster Roll of Company D, 11th Regiment, Arkansas Volunteers, February 28, 1863 [Enclosure]
    Muster Roll of Company K, 53th Regiment, N. C. [?] Troops, August, 1863
    Muster Roll of Company K, Phillips Regiment, March 1, 1864 [Gift of Charles Gibson, Buffalo, June 9, 1891]
    Muster Roll of Company E, Third. Regiment, Alabama Volunteers, November 1, 1864 [from Eaten Papers - enclosure]
    Letter to B.H.S. from George Williams, describing seizure of "Queen of West" Stemmer by Confederate Sympathizers; Presentation of Confederate Flag to B.H.S., March 13, 1900
  - Other military recruitment papers, 1862-1864 (Box-folder 5.7)
- Reminiscences, 1887-1891, XII.
  - Madison Buell: Mounted clippings of published recollections of his involvement in Civil War telegraphy, 1887-1891 (Box-folder 5.8)
  - W.W. Potter, M.D.: "Three Years with the Army of the Potomac: A Personal Military History," 1888, (typescript) (Box-folder 5.9)
- W.T. Anderson Collection, 1861-1865, XIII.
  - Autographs and communications from prominent military [and non-military] persons in the service of the United [and Confederate] States during the Great Rebellion, 1861- 1865 (Box-folder 6.1)
  - Maps of the Battles of Bull Run and Chattanooga; blank Confederate commissioning certificate for vessels, 1861; oil requisition form, 1861 (Box-folder 6.2)
- Diary Excerpts, Autographs, Emblems, and Papers Concerning Unidentified Regiments and Soldiers, XIV.
  - Excerpts from diary and letters of Elizabeth Knowles (wife of R. Wells Knowles, Orleans County) 1861-1863 (Box-folder 6.3)
  - Autographs, undated (Box-folder 6.4)
  - 2nd Army Corps, subsistence account book, Brooks Station, April-May 1863 (Box-folder 6.5)
  - John Ketchum collection of Civil War emblems (Box-folder 6.6)
  - Mounted specimens of Civil War envelopes and emblems (Box-folder 6.7)
  - Miscellaneous (War record of Edward Annis Merrill, [1864] passes; ballets; scripture passages; subscription coupons: letters; etc.) (Box-folder 6.8)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Contributors
Wilkeson, Samuel, 1817-1889; Matteson, Carl; Eaton, John B.; Knowles, Elizabeth; Stoddard, George N.; Hayward, John A.; Johnson, Charles E.; Brown, James Malcolm, d. 1862; Granger, Warren; Barney, L.L.; Buell, Madison, b. 1834; Potter, William Warren, 1837-1911; Confederate States of America. Army; Buffalo History Museum
Subject Terms
Veterans--New York (State); United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; United States. Army--Recruiting, enlistment, etc.--Civil War, 1861-1865; Orleans County (N.Y.)--History--Civil War, 1861-1865
Genre Terms
Muster rolls; Diaries; Discharges; Autographs; Maps; Reminiscences; Military records